Ali Hassan Fouanne

Front End Web Developer

Contact info

Address: Ajman-United Arab Emirates Phone: —----- Email: alifouanne8@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-fouanne-56b602222/ Github: https://github.com/Alifouanne

Portfolio: https://ali-fouanne.vercel.app/

Summary

Software engineer with nearly two years of experience in developing front-end websites using popular frameworks such as React JS and Next JS. Demonstrating adeptness in leveraging a wide range of libraries and packages to enhance the development process, resulting in efficient and feature-rich web applications.

Technical Skills

JavaScript

• HTML

CSS

SQL

• C++

JQuery

React JS

Next JS

Tailwind CSS

Redux

Zustand

Material UI

React Query

TypeScript

Sass

Responsive design

Git

Github

Bitbucket

Experience

Software Engineer - Innovura , Homs-Syria Arab Republic (Remote)

Jul 2023 - Sep 2023

- Successfully developed part of the user interface for a nursery school website using Next.js.
- Leveraged Tailwind CSS to create visually appealing and responsive designs.
- Designed and implemented a robust PostgreSQL database, creating an Entity Relationship Diagram (ERD) to ensure efficient data management and integrity.
- Utilized Prisma ORM to establish a seamless connection between the website and the PostgreSQL database.
- Initialized and integrated the React Big Calendar library, Implement event management functionality, allowing users to add and manage events within the calendar.
- Leveraged NextAuth for authentication, integrating Google Provider for user authentication and enhancing the security of the website.
- Incorporated Shadon/ui components into the website, enhancing the user interface with intuitive and visually appealing UI elements.

Front-end Developer - Freelancer , Homs-Syrian Arab Republic

Dec 2021 - May 2023

- Collaborated with a team in developing a Teaching Institute Management Program using Java and MySQL.
- Collaborated with a team in developing an Android job search app in Java, integrated with Firebase. Enabled users to find jobs conveniently.
- Designed a gym website using React, featuring animations for enhanced user experience.
- Built a React-based cryptocurrency info site using external APIs for real-time data.
- Developed an AI-driven chat platform, allowing interactions with multiple AI models.
- Crafted a weather website using StepZen,GraphQL,Next js for real-time forecasts.
- Created an e-commerce website using Next.js and Redux for shopping, delivering seamless user experiences and robust state management.
- Developed an e-commerce website for a makeup store, leveraging WordPress, WooCommerce, and Elementor. Designed to showcase products and facilitate seamless purchasing, this website contributed to an enhanced online shopping experience.

Education

Master in Web Science

Syrian Virtual University | Homs, Syria Jan 2023 - present

Bachelor of Software Engineering GPA: 2.96

Al-Baath University | Homs,Syria Sep 2015 - Sep 2021

Relevant Coursework: OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Systems, Software Engineering Logic Design, Computer, Graphics, Linear Algebra, Digital Signal Processing, Image Processing, Data Analytics

Languages

Arabic (Native)

- English (Intermediate)

Projects

Cloud - Weather App

<u>Github</u>

A weather app with comprehensive city information, featuring cutting-edge technology, an intuitive UI, and a sleek design.

Technologies: Next js , Tremor UI , Stepzen , Tailwind CSS

Amazon clone
Github

A feature-rich e-commerce platform replicating Amazon's functionality and user experience **Technologies**: Next js , Firebase , Next Auth , Tailwind CSS , React Query , Zustand , Stripe

• Crypto-Website Github

This crypto website offers comprehensive information and news on diverse cryptocurrencies.

Technologies: React js , Vite , Antd , Redux toolkit , RTK Query , Chart js , Framer motion , React Router